<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ervanalb/blog - Adventures</title><link href="https://eric.van.al/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://eric.van.al/feeds/adventures.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://eric.van.al/</id><updated>2018-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Canyoning and Diving in Australia</title><link href="https://eric.van.al/canyoning-and-diving-in-australia.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:eric.van.al,2018-12-30:/canyoning-and-diving-in-australia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sabrina had just finished wintering over at the south pole,
and had a plane ticket to anywhere in the world.
She decided to plan a four-part trip that involved
hiking in New Zealand,
canyoning in Australia,
diving the Great Barrier Reef,
and climbing in Thailand.
I joined for the middle two segments, and got to do some fun canyoning and diving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/abseil.jpg" title="Abseiling a waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/abseil.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/turtle.jpg" title="Turtle munching some coral"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/turtle.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sabrina had just finished wintering over at the south pole,
and had a plane ticket to anywhere in the world.
She decided to plan a four-part trip that involved
hiking in New Zealand,
canyoning in Australia,
diving the Great Barrier Reef,
and climbing in Thailand.
I joined for the middle two segments, and got to do some fun canyoning and diving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/abseil.jpg" title="Abseiling a waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/abseil.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/turtle.jpg" title="Turtle munching some coral"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/turtle.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Canyoning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crew for the canyoning portion of the trip
was composed of Rassi, Sabrina, and me.
The landscape of the canyons was fairly similar to the United States.
One thing that surprised me was the amount of vegetation
in the sandstone canyons.
I'm used to Zion, which is basically a desert,
so you get bare rock faces.
In Australia, it was fairly common for a slot to open out
into a short section of forest.
There were also glow worms in the dark sections of the slot canyons.
One of the canyons had a cave with hundreds of them lighting the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/canyon-jungle.jpg" title="Greenery in a sandstone canyon"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/canyon-jungle.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite canyon was &lt;em&gt;Kanangra Main&lt;/em&gt;.
It was the only granite canyon we did,
and it certainly lived up to its class-C rating.
The canyon is basically just a series of several multi-pitch rappels
straight down a set of waterfalls,
totalling a few hundred meters.
There is probably only about 40 minutes of creek walking in the whole canyon,
with 20 minutes at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/kanangra-main.jpg" title="Abseiling in Kanangra Main"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/kanangra-main.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exit hike is to go straight up "murdering gully,"
which the beta said would take about 1.5 hours.
We started straight up the valley,
and encountered several vertical cliffs,
with just enough water trickling down to make them slippery.
After a few sketchy climbs up these, we departed from the valley
and began a meandering bushwalk with no obvious path.
We got cliffed out a few times, and had to take our best guess
at how to proceed upwards.
The route was covered in stinging spear grass
and a rare kind of tree with big flat leaves
that stung much worse.
After 4.5 hours we finally emerged onto the ridgeline trail
that brought us back to the starting point.
That night, we talked with some local canyoneers who were
staying at the same campsite as us.
We described the ridiculous route we took up murdering gully,
complete with the sketchy climbs and stinging plants.
The locals said that we had navigated the gully
exactly as intended, and thought it was ridiculous that
it had taken us more than an hour and a half.
That night we picked leeches off ourselves,
except for Rassi, who didn't find theirs until the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience, along with the other canyons we did,
has led me to the conclusion that Aussies are &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; better at hiking that Americans,
but slower at rappelling.
They also have a strange fear of water,
with many canyons calling for "lilos," or inflatable mattresses
to float on down streams.
We bought some and used them in the canyons,
and while entertaining and novel,
didn't seem necessary or practical in most situations.
Nevertheless, I'm definitely considering packing one
for next time I'm in the Sierras and faced with a 100' swim.
Mostly, I just want to see the look on everyones face
when I start inflating a pool toy in the middle of a
swiftwater canyon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/lilo.jpg" title="Rassi inflating a lilo"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/lilo.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the wildest experiences happened not while canyoning,
but while driving.
We were headed for the Kanangra campground,
having been warned by the book that it was a long hard drive.
It was late at night and we were tired.
We caught a glimpse what looked like a giant lit-up cliff face looming in front of us.
The road became narrow and winding and started winding downwards.
At the bottom of the treacherous switchbacks,
we found ourselves at the base of the lit-up cliff.
The road became one lane and went underground,
through a natural tunnel formed by the Grand Arch of the
&lt;a href="https://www.jenolancaves.org.au/"&gt;Jenolan cave system&lt;/a&gt;.
I was definitely not expecting the highway to the campsite
to turn into a cave, and driving through it in the dark
was a surreal experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/jenolan.jpg" title="Walking through the Jenolan caves"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/jenolan.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was dissapointed that the Australians don't call
"&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Australian_rappel"&gt;aussie rappelling&lt;/a&gt;" just "rappelling."
I did Aussie rap down the last pitch of Kanangra Main,
just to be able to say that I had gone Aussie rappelling in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/aussie-rappel.jpg" title="Aussie rapping the last pitch of Kanangra Main"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/aussie-rappel.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;"Diving"&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crystal, Danny, and I were all certified before going to Australia.
Sabrina was planning on getting certified there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crystal, Danny, and I made two dives together.
The first we did unguided.
I had a lot of trouble navigating,
and Crystal had some bouyancy control issues which led to us getting separated.
We surfaced far from the boat, regrouped on the surface, and had to be towed back in.
We got a guide for the second dive, which went much better.
After that, Danny and Sabrina transferred to the liveaboard vessel
where they would do another dive and spend the night.
Crystal and I went home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second day, Crystal and I made another two dives on the same boat, both guided.
Our first dive had five people.
One person had bouyancy control issues fairly early and surfaced.
Another person got lost from the group a little farther along.
Our guide indicated to me, Crystal, and the third remaining group member
to kneel on the bottom and wait, while he searched for the missing group members.
While waiting, the third remaining person saw another group swim by,
thought it was our group, and left to join them.
The instructor returned, having failed to locate any of the other divers,
to learn that there were now three missing.
We surfaced and waited, and eventually found everybody who had gotten lost,
but there were definitely some tense moments.
The fourth dive was with a much smaller group, and we had no issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reef itself was quite cool,
and we got to see a bunch of wildlife
including turtles and reef sharks.
However, the trip was plagued by poor conditions.
It was rainy, which wasn't really a problem once underwater,
but the moderately stormy weather made the sea incredibly rough.
The 2-hour boat ride each way led to more than half of the participants
getting seasick.
By the second day, the boat began to smell noticably of vomit.
The rough sea churned up a lot of particulates leading to poor visibility.
When it was good, you could see maybe 5 meters, and when it was bad,
it was hard to see 3.
Given the conditions, it was unsurprising that so many people got lost.
This, combined with the high cost of boat rides out to the reef,
led us to only do two days of diving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/shark.jpg" title="A reef shark"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/shark.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We bummed around for a few days in Cairns.
We rented a car and visited some waterfalls (but didn't rappel any.)
We saw the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curtain_Fig_Tree"&gt;curtain fig tree&lt;/a&gt;
and cooked some kangaroo on the barbie.
We went to Chillagoe and ducked into a super awesome cave system,
which we only discovered the vastness of while stumbling around
looking for the exit.
We even called in a bush fire we spotted while driving back,
and got to stargaze in the southern hemisphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/crystal-cave.jpg" title="Crystal in a cave"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-australia/thumbnails/_x320/crystal-cave.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe id="ytplayer" type="text/html" width="640" height="360"
  src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_Fjt-0B1BW0"
  frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="canyons"></category><category term="ropes"></category><category term="scuba"></category><category term="caves"></category></entry><entry><title>Canyoning in Ouray</title><link href="https://eric.van.al/canyoning-in-ouray.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:eric.van.al,2018-08-25:/canyoning-in-ouray.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the month between leaving work and starting grad school,
Larissa did a bunch of outdoor adventuring.
I joined her for a week of canyoning in Colorado,
along with Maya and Josh.
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the month between leaving work and starting grad school,
Larissa did a bunch of outdoor adventuring.
I joined her for a week of canyoning in Colorado,
along with Maya and Josh.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed to consistently rain in the afternoon,
which frequently foiled our canyon plans.
Some of the canyons had nasty-looking floodwater
and were kicking small rocks over their falls.
We did a lot of non-canyoning activities,
including going to a &lt;a href="https://www.sanjuancountyhistoricalsociety.org/index.html"&gt;super awesome mining museum&lt;/a&gt;
and eating funnel cake.
I tried to do a day hike,
but couldn't handle the altitude and turned back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, we managed to get in a handful of canyons.
There was a super fun canyon called &lt;a href="http://ropewiki.com/Cascade_Creek_(Durango_Waterpark)"&gt;Durango Waterpark&lt;/a&gt;.
After the first run, we learned that the whole loop only took about 30 minutes, and that all of the obstacles were safe to jump.
We went back a few days later without any packs or technical gear.
Josh, Maya, and I climbed down to the creek while Larissa waited in the car.
After about 20 minutes of hiking downstream,
we encountered a bridge that we hadn't passed before
and realized that we had dropped into the wrong canyon.
We went back upstream 20 minutes and found a very worried
Larissa, who had also realized we had dropped into the wrong place.
Thankfully, it is hard to make any committing moves without any gear.
We went to the correct canyon and ran it twice through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have video footage from this trip, but I haven't had time to edit it yet.
Once I'm done with the highlights reel, I will post it here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="canyons"></category><category term="ropes"></category></entry><entry><title>Summerfest 2018</title><link href="https://eric.van.al/summerfest-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:eric.van.al,2018-08-05:/summerfest-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Banks, Maggie and I went to Summerfest at Skydive Chicago,
where we made a bunch of jumps and generally had a great time.
Notably, we put together two &lt;a href="https://alum.mit.edu/slice/its-bird-its-plane-its-mit-skydivers"&gt;MIT record jumps&lt;/a&gt;
from the assortment of alums who happened to be attending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-summerfest/sky.jpg" title="MIT skydivers forming a T in the sky"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-summerfest/thumbnails/_x320/sky.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-summerfest/ground.jpg" title="Group photo of the MIT record participants"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-summerfest/thumbnails/_x320/ground.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Banks, Maggie and I went to Summerfest at Skydive Chicago,
where we made a bunch of jumps and generally had a great time.
Notably, we put together two &lt;a href="https://alum.mit.edu/slice/its-bird-its-plane-its-mit-skydivers"&gt;MIT record jumps&lt;/a&gt;
from the assortment of alums who happened to be attending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-summerfest/sky.jpg" title="MIT skydivers forming a T in the sky"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-summerfest/thumbnails/_x320/sky.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-summerfest/ground.jpg" title="Group photo of the MIT record participants"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-summerfest/thumbnails/_x320/ground.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After assembling the 11-way belly jump,
Banks organized a 5-way head down jump
with myself, Maggie, Swati, and Steve,
with JRuss on camera.
Steve didn't have much head down experience,
so we mostly built around him.
On break-off, he forgot to turn 180 before tracking away
and plowed right into me.
Everyone was fine and we laughed it off on the ground.
He definitely got some shit from JRuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a handful of videos clips from this event, and will probably post them here eventually.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="skydiving"></category></entry><entry><title>Hard canyons in Zion</title><link href="https://eric.van.al/hard-canyons-in-zion.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:eric.van.al,2018-06-05:/hard-canyons-in-zion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Zach, dlaw, Ionna and I went to Zion in the summer 2018.
After doing a lot of beginner "intro to canyoning" trips,
it was nice to power through some of the harder canyons in that area.
We even ran into Itaru near the end of our trip, and he joined us for our last canyon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-zion/rappel.jpg" title="Zach and dlaw"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-zion/thumbnails/_x320/rappel.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-zion/imlay-final.jpg" title="Zach on the final rappel of Imlay"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-zion/thumbnails/_x320/imlay-final.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Zach, dlaw, Ionna and I went to Zion in the summer 2018.
After doing a lot of beginner "intro to canyoning" trips,
it was nice to power through some of the harder canyons in that area.
We even ran into Itaru near the end of our trip, and he joined us for our last canyon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-zion/rappel.jpg" title="Zach and dlaw"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-zion/thumbnails/_x320/rappel.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-zion/imlay-final.jpg" title="Zach on the final rappel of Imlay"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-zion/thumbnails/_x320/imlay-final.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most memorable canyon was definitely &lt;a href="https://www.canyoneeringusa.com/zion/technical/imlay-sneak-route"&gt;Imlay&lt;/a&gt;.
The canyon has 40+ obstacles. It was our first time doing pothole escapes, and we weren't planning on taking more than one day
(though we were prepared to do an emergency bivvy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a strenuous entrance hike, the first obstacle was the "trash compactor",
named after the &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/7U3Oti2L8S4?t=105"&gt;scene from star wars&lt;/a&gt;.
After rappelling into deep water in a narrow slot, you are faced with a swim of about 100 feet.
The catch is that the path is completely blocked up with floating logs and debris.
The logs are too large to just shove out of the way,
but not bouyant enough to stand on.
The only way to make forward progress is to tread water,
while slowly rearranging the logs to make forward progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first obstacle took us 40 minutes,
and we were absolutely convinced that we were out of our league.
We were mentally preparing to spend the the better half of a week slowly making our way through
forty more trash compactors.
Thankfully, the rest of the obstacles were much more straightforward.
The canyon was fun and challenging,
and we made it out before nightfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The canyon finishes with a 100' free-hanging rappel into the narrows.
There were tourists directly in the fall line of our rope,
so we flaked the rope and lowered it down hand-over-hand so as to not drop it on their heads.
They didn't even notice that there were people above them
until the first person was nearly finished with the rappel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe id="ytplayer" type="text/html" width="640" height="360"
  src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2L--mIN1uF8"
  frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;List of canyons we did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.canyoneeringusa.com/zion/technical/keyhole"&gt;Keyhole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.canyoneeringusa.com/zion/technical/middle-echo"&gt;Echo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.canyoneeringusa.com/zion/technical/imlay-sneak-route"&gt;Imlay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.canyoneeringusa.com/zion/technical/spry"&gt;Spry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.canyoneeringusa.com/zion/technical/orderville"&gt;Orderville&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.canyoneeringusa.com/zion/technical/pine-creek"&gt;Pine Creek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="canyons"></category><category term="ropes"></category></entry><entry><title>SCUBA in Cancun</title><link href="https://eric.van.al/scuba-in-cancun.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:eric.van.al,2018-04-10:/scuba-in-cancun.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In April of 2018, some friends and I went to do some SCUBA diving in Cancun and Cozumel.
We had five days of great diving, including seeing the MUSA underwater museum and doing some
cavern diving in the cenotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-cancun/turtle.jpg" title="Larissa and a turtle"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-cancun/thumbnails/_x320/turtle.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-cancun/cenote.jpg" title="Inside a cenote looking out"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-cancun/thumbnails/_x320/cenote.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In April of 2018, some friends and I went to do some SCUBA diving in Cancun and Cozumel.
We had five days of great diving, including seeing the MUSA underwater museum and doing some
cavern diving in the cenotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-cancun/turtle.jpg" title="Larissa and a turtle"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-cancun/thumbnails/_x320/turtle.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-cancun/cenote.jpg" title="Inside a cenote looking out"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/2018-cancun/thumbnails/_x320/cenote.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe id="ytplayer" type="text/html" width="640" height="360"
  src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n6kJ8dX20CY"
  frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="scuba"></category></entry><entry><title>Canyoning in the Sierras</title><link href="https://eric.van.al/canyoning-in-the-sierras.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:eric.van.al,2016-08-16:/canyoning-in-the-sierras.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In summer of 2016, we took a trip to the Sierras in California to descend some canyons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/down_canyon.jpg" title="The view down-canyon"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x320/down_canyon.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/teacups.jpg" title="7 Teacups"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x320/teacups.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In summer of 2016, we took a trip to the Sierras in California to descend some canyons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/down_canyon.jpg" title="The view down-canyon"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x320/down_canyon.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/teacups.jpg" title="7 Teacups"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x320/teacups.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, we did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ropewiki.com/Basin_Creek"&gt;Basin Creek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ropewiki.com/Pittman_Creek_(Another_Dam_Canyon)"&gt;Pittman Creek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ropewiki.com/Jump_Trip_(Upper)"&gt;Upper Jump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ropewiki.com/Big_Creek_(Canyon_of_the_Dammed)"&gt;Big Creek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ropewiki.com/Shaver_Cut_(Upper_Stevenson_Creek)"&gt;Shaver's Cut&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ropewiki.com/Jump_Trip_(Lower)"&gt;Lower Jump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ropewiki.com/Jose_Creek"&gt;Jose Creek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ropewiki.com/Seven_Teacups"&gt;7 Teacups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There aren't many pictures because I was using my phone, which is not waterproof. Keep this in mind when viewing some of the shots I did get!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/up_canyon.jpg" title="The view up-canyon"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x240/up_canyon.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/waterfall.jpg" title="A waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x240/waterfall.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/eric_rock.jpg" title="Eric sitting on a rock"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x240/eric_rock.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/crystal.jpg" title="Crystal"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x240/crystal.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/kamal_liz.jpg" title="Kamal and Liz"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x240/kamal_liz.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/sabrina_maya_becca.jpg" title="Sabrina, Maya, Becca"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x240/sabrina_maya_becca.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/zbanks.jpg" title="zbanks"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x240/zbanks.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbs_up.gif" title="Thumbs up"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbs_up.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/sadun_waterfall.gif" title="Sadun descending a waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/sadun_waterfall.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/vicki_waterfall.gif" title="Vicki descending a waterfall"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/vicki_waterfall.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/graceful.gif" title="Crystal being graceful"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/graceful.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/zbanks_flop.gif" title="Zach flopping"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/zbanks_flop.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/crystal_jump.gif" title="Crystal jumping (Upper jump)"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/crystal_jump.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/maya_jump.gif" title="Maya jumping (Upper jump)"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/maya_jump.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/eric_jump.gif" title="Eric jumping (Upper jump)"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/eric_jump.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/maya_rappel.gif" title="Maya rappelling (Upper jump)"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/maya_rappel.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/crystal_rappel.gif" title="Crystal rappelling (Upper jump)"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/crystal_rappel.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/zbanks_rappel.gif" title="Zach rappelling (Upper jump)"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/zbanks_rappel.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/maya.jpg" title="Maya"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x240/maya.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/maya_jump_teacups.gif" title="Maya jumping (7 teacups)"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/maya_jump_teacups.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/zbanks_jump_teacups.gif" title="Zach jumping (7 teacups)"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/zbanks_jump_teacups.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/zbanks_maya.jpg" title="Zach and Maya chilling in the pool"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/canyoning/thumbnails/_x240/zbanks_maya.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="canyons"></category><category term="ropes"></category></entry><entry><title>Early years of skydiving</title><link href="https://eric.van.al/early-years-of-skydiving.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:eric.van.al,2016-06-26:/early-years-of-skydiving.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Landing in planes is scary, so I usually leave before that happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/landing.jpg" title="Landing under my Pilot 150"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/thumbnails/_x320/landing.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Landing in planes is scary, so I usually leave before that happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/landing.jpg" title="Landing under my Pilot 150"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/thumbnails/_x320/landing.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/belly.jpg" title="Student gear"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/thumbnails/_x320/belly.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/storm.jpg" title="My first canopy: Storm 170"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/thumbnails/_x320/storm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/angle.jpg" title="Angle flying"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/thumbnails/_x320/angle.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/angle_2.jpg" title="More angle"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://eric.van.al/media/skydiving/thumbnails/_x320/angle_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P6N6KaRBHNU"&gt;AFF: Cat D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ch7c82DToJU"&gt;Jump 48&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0U1HeNA7ClU"&gt;Hybrid Attempt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2xVc4HfttJs"&gt;Angle Flying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="skydiving"></category></entry></feed>